<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Verse For Barric</title>
    <link>/overview/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A Verse For Barric</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/overview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggressive Spells</title>
      <link>/overview/aggressive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/aggressive/</guid>
      <description>Aggressive spells are meant to kill the enemy before they can kill you. This is done by direct damage, or by increasing the damage your units can do. The spells also compliment one another, so that when stacked can do massive damage.
All of the spells use Fire as the element.
High damage, low control, low debuffs, low healing.
Phoenix     Level 1 Level 2 Level 3      Dead units damage engaged target.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boss Progression</title>
      <link>/overview/boss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/boss/</guid>
      <description>Sand Shaman The shaman appears in Level 3 : City and is our first encounter with a boss. This boss isn&amp;rsquo;t a boss like the others &amp;ndash; it becomes a normal champion later in the game. Other bosses are one time encounters, but this just introduces the player to dealing with enemy spell casters. So, the goal is to treat the unit like a boss during the first 2 sequences, and then make it a traditional squad based unit that can be killed for the final sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Spells</title>
      <link>/overview/controlling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/controlling/</guid>
      <description>Controlling spells will probably be the most difficult to play. They will requires more switching between spell categories. For example, mesmerize a unit, then switch to Protective and play for awhile, then switch back to Controlling. They also have wave based triggers (wave starts, heal units), so the player will have to switch at the correct timing.
All of the spells use Wind / Mind as the element.
Moderate damage, high control, moderate debuffs, low healing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enemy Progression</title>
      <link>/overview/enemy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/enemy/</guid>
      <description>Bad Melee 1 : Border Squires This is the first and most common enemy unit, and it counters Melee 1. Also allows for the largest enemy squads. Only has a base attack. Gradually levels up and sticks around throughout the game.
Starting Level: 0
   Attack Defense Fortitude Strength Agility Magic Recruit Bandage Max Squad     Slashing - 1 1 1 1 1 1 24    Bad Archer 1 : Border Hunter This first enemy archer squad starts the game on the first level as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friendly Progression</title>
      <link>/overview/friendly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/friendly/</guid>
      <description>Melee 1 : Lemon Knights This unit begins the game with you. They represent the base unit. That said, all units should be valid, so these guys can make up for in numbers what they lack in ability. Cheapest to recruit / expand this squad.
Starting Level: 0
   Attack Defense Fortitude Strength Agility Magic Recruit Bandage Max Squad     Slashing - 1 1 1 1 1 1 24    Melee 2 : Ice Guard Cassandra sends these troops to aid you against the enemy archers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gameplay Progression</title>
      <link>/overview/gameplay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/gameplay/</guid>
      <description>:question: Decision : Select your base magic type.
Before the player begins, they can choose their preferred magic type. This selection will allow Level 1 to be played without interruption.
:movie_camera: Movie : Intro : Scene 1
Explains Barric&amp;rsquo;s backstory, and establishes where the player is now. Scene is actually the same scene as level 12, since the first 11 levels are played in the past and the player is brought up to real time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protective Spells</title>
      <link>/overview/protective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/protective/</guid>
      <description>Protective spells are meant to keep your friendlies alive. This is done by direct healing, revival, or by limiting the amount of damage an enemy can do. Crowd control is minimal, with Smite being the only hope of Fear / Stun in a hard fight.
All of the spells use Water / Magic as the element.
Low damage, low control, low debuffs, high healing.
Heal     Level 1 Level 2 Level 3      Heal units for 25HP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Ideas</title>
      <link>/overview/ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/ideas/</guid>
      <description>This is just a dump of ideas. Add them here for future brainstorming.
Major Game Engine Features To Be Considered Code that I haven&amp;rsquo;t added yet.
Flanking bonus Strategic positions Treasure chests Larger maps Heroes Items Difficulty Level Boss Fights Player places units Hidden units (i.e: placed behind tree)  Difficulty Level Games are annoying when you have to start them over completely &amp;ndash; especially story heavy games. One option is to offer easy mode and normal mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical Notes</title>
      <link>/overview/tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/tech/</guid>
      <description>A place to store random tech notes for reference when designing things.
Modifiers There are a few types of modifiers in the game, and they are all applied in different ways. Here&amp;rsquo;s the breakdown of how a unit might get a modifier applied to it.
 Spell Modifiers: Each spell applies a modifier to the target squad / units and this can be overridden on the spell level. Spells are abilities, and they should process ability modifiers the same way combat modifiers do, but they currently don&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watchful Spells</title>
      <link>/overview/watchful/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/watchful/</guid>
      <description>Watchful spells are well balanced. They should be able to heal units, buff units, resist damage, do damage, and offer crowd control.
All of the spells use Nature as the element.
Moderate damage, moderate control, moderate debuffs, moderate healing.
Regen     Level 1 Level 2 Level 3      Heal a unit for 25 HP every tick. Purify negative effects on unit when cast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Map</title>
      <link>/overview/map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/map/</guid>
      <description>Names &amp;amp; Locations  Barric: One of the council lords, and Stou&amp;rsquo;s older brother. Stou: Stou&amp;rsquo;s younger brother who the player is controlling. Alfric: The knight Stou is talking to at the beginning. One of the council members, Barric&amp;rsquo;s equal. South Keep: Barric&amp;rsquo;s city Cassandra: Princess to king Barric overthrew. Barric still helps her. Stou has a crush. Wintry Manor: Cassandra&amp;rsquo;s ice city Mountains of Arrington: Mountain range that Wintry Manor lies in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>