<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Verse For Barric</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A Verse For Barric</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggressive Spells</title>
      <link>/overview/aggressive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/aggressive/</guid>
      <description>Aggressive spells are meant to kill the enemy before they can kill you. This is done by direct damage, or by increasing the damage your units can do. The spells also compliment one another, so that when stacked can do massive damage.
All of the spells use Fire as the element.
High damage, low control, low debuffs, low healing.
Phoenix     Level 1 Level 2 Level 3      Dead units damage engaged target.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animations</title>
      <link>/animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/animations/</guid>
      <description>I began working with Liron Peer in late 2014 on character animations. Of all the specialties, finding an animator who could work on isometric material was the biggest challenge. I spent over $1,000 on trial runs through various animators with no luck. Once I found Liron and she nailed her first attempt, we jumped straight in to the entire contract. In total, she produced over 1,000 hand drawn frames. Here are a few of them:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Betrayal : Scene 7</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene7/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and CASSANDRA interrogating ISS&amp;rsquo;DAR after the battle.
Stou  Why do you attack us? Who leads this assault? Tell me, now.
 Iss&amp;rsquo;dar  You fool. The answer is in front of you.
 Stou  You dare give me riddles?
 Iss&amp;rsquo;dar  Are you so blind? You&amp;rsquo;ve been betrayed.
 Enemy army appears on the horizon.
Stou  We were followed &amp;hellip; how? They didn&amp;rsquo;t know we were here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boss Progression</title>
      <link>/overview/boss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/boss/</guid>
      <description>Sand Shaman The shaman appears in Level 3 : City and is our first encounter with a boss. This boss isn&amp;rsquo;t a boss like the others &amp;ndash; it becomes a normal champion later in the game. Other bosses are one time encounters, but this just introduces the player to dealing with enemy spell casters. So, the goal is to treat the unit like a boss during the first 2 sequences, and then make it a traditional squad based unit that can be killed for the final sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BroDown : Scene 10</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene10/</guid>
      <description> Current cutscene implementation
No dialogue. STOU kills BARRIC, and flashbacks explain how he was set up.
TODO / DISCUSS Decide if we want snow or not. Fix flashbacks based off of updated visuals. 09:19 - Glint chains to highlight he was captive NOTES: Travel dialogue to hammer home that she orchestrated all of this.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camp : Scene 11</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene11/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and ALFRIC resume there conversation from the beginning of the game, explaining why they&amp;rsquo;re gathered for war.
Stou  That&amp;rsquo;s why we&amp;rsquo;re gathered here to fight.
 Alfric  So, Barric is truly gone then. It hurts to say that out loud. That traitorous b&amp;hellip; clearly her father&amp;rsquo;s blood runs deep.
 Stou  What news of her army?
 Alfric  She marches for the castle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code</title>
      <link>/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/code/</guid>
      <description>To date, this game has 38,378 lines of Swift code. There have been countless hours invested in art, story, design, animation and brainstorming, but code makes all of this tick. Behind the scenes, SpriteKit and GameplayKit power a vast majority of the engine. This section provides a look at some of the custom frameworks that had to be developed along with tricky problems that had to be solved.
The Frameworks CutsceneKit Helps develop chat overlays with custom timing and movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Spells</title>
      <link>/overview/controlling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/controlling/</guid>
      <description>Controlling spells will probably be the most difficult to play. They will requires more switching between spell categories. For example, mesmerize a unit, then switch to Protective and play for awhile, then switch back to Controlling. They also have wave based triggers (wave starts, heal units), so the player will have to switch at the correct timing.
All of the spells use Wind / Mind as the element.
Moderate damage, high control, moderate debuffs, low healing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossroads : Scene 8</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene8/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and CASSANDRA at crossroads deciding next steps.
Stou  Still they persist.
 Cassandra  Perhaps, we should split up.
 Stou  I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy the idea of dividing our forces. Or, of leaving you.
 Cassandra  Nor do I, but hear me. Lure them into the mountains, distract them, I will alert the council.
 Stou  I don&amp;rsquo;t like this, Cassandra. But, you&amp;rsquo;re right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision : Scene 4</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene4/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and CASSANDRA consult with BARRIC after the battle at SOUTH KEEP
Cassandra  Our ambush was avoided.
 Barric  I know, and had we pressed the attack, our city would have been left defenseless. We must not overreact.
 Stou  Overreact? They attacked our city, Barric. Our home!
 Barric  And who exactly are &amp;ldquo;they&amp;rdquo;?
 Stou  This matters when they bring war to our very doorstep?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distraction : Scene 3</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene3/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and CASSANDRA notice the main force bypassed their ambush and is marching on South Keep.
Cassandra  The whole of their forces approaches the city!
 Stou  How did they get past us?
 Cassandra  It seems the attack was but a small diversion all the while the real threat marched from the south.
 Stou  They knew we were waiting. But &amp;hellip; how?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enemy Progression</title>
      <link>/overview/enemy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/enemy/</guid>
      <description>Bad Melee 1 : Border Squires This is the first and most common enemy unit, and it counters Melee 1. Also allows for the largest enemy squads. Only has a base attack. Gradually levels up and sticks around throughout the game.
Starting Level: 0
   Attack Defense Fortitude Strength Agility Magic Recruit Bandage Max Squad     Slashing - 1 1 1 1 1 1 24    Bad Archer 1 : Border Hunter This first enemy archer squad starts the game on the first level as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fjord : Scene 9</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene9/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and TOWNSMEN discussing why the Manor has been abandoned.
Stou  Townsmen, where is everyone?
 Townsmen  They left, sir. About 2 3 weeks past. Marching towards the war.
 Stou  2 3 weeks ago? The war hadn&amp;rsquo;t begun yet. Who ordered this?
 Townsmen  Orders came down from &amp;hellip; Sir! We&amp;rsquo;re under attack!
 TODO / DISCUSS 08:41 - Revisit snow effect 08:45 - Blinking Stou 08:52 - Something like pan to incoming army, change in dialogue, or somehting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friendly Progression</title>
      <link>/overview/friendly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/friendly/</guid>
      <description>Melee 1 : Lemon Knights This unit begins the game with you. They represent the base unit. That said, all units should be valid, so these guys can make up for in numbers what they lack in ability. Cheapest to recruit / expand this squad.
Starting Level: 0
   Attack Defense Fortitude Strength Agility Magic Recruit Bandage Max Squad     Slashing - 1 1 1 1 1 1 24    Melee 2 : Ice Guard Cassandra sends these troops to aid you against the enemy archers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gameplay Progression</title>
      <link>/overview/gameplay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/gameplay/</guid>
      <description>:question: Decision : Select your base magic type.
Before the player begins, they can choose their preferred magic type. This selection will allow Level 1 to be played without interruption.
:movie_camera: Movie : Intro : Scene 1
Explains Barric&amp;rsquo;s backstory, and establishes where the player is now. Scene is actually the same scene as level 12, since the first 11 levels are played in the past and the player is brought up to real time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illustrations</title>
      <link>/illustrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/illustrations/</guid>
      <description>Scott Pellico was a godsend for this project. After a few trial runs with other artists, I was having trouble establishing an art direction. My brother, Chris, found Scott for his project. Since Chris didn&amp;rsquo;t need Scott full time, Scott agreed to split his work between the two of us. He worked on the project part time for nearly a year starting in 2014. Before getting into specific contributions, here is a gallery of some of my favorite Scott creations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro : Scene 1</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene1/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and ALFRIC gathered amongst soldiers setting up camp.
Stou  You&amp;rsquo;ve met my brother, Barric?
 Alfric  Met him? I&amp;rsquo;ve fought with him, and would again. Fine warrior, and a better man.
 Stou  I never knew that side of him. I&amp;rsquo;ve only heard stories.
 Alfric  Story like his &amp;hellip; words only carry so much. Don&amp;rsquo;t do it justice. Barric saved this kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intruder : Scene 2</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene2/</guid>
      <description>STOU and ALFRIC and CASSANDRA examining an invaders corpse.
Cassandra  These markings, this soldier is from the Drylands. This makes no sense. What would prompt such an attack?
 Stou  We need to find out. We&amp;rsquo;ll track those who escaped.
 Barric  No. We must return to South Keep and warn our people.
 Stou  Turn back? And what then, Barric? Wait to be attacked again?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motion Graphics</title>
      <link>/motion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/motion/</guid>
      <description>The term motion graphics doesn&amp;rsquo;t justify the help that Brian Campbell provided on this project. He began contributing in March 2015 as a video editor for cutscenes. That alone was huge. At the time, I had the story written and art for the scenes designed. I quickly stitched them together in iMovie to get a sense for pacing. Fortunately, Brian does this stuff for a living so he knew exactly what needed to happen to move things forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protective Spells</title>
      <link>/overview/protective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/protective/</guid>
      <description>Protective spells are meant to keep your friendlies alive. This is done by direct healing, revival, or by limiting the amount of damage an enemy can do. Crowd control is minimal, with Smite being the only hope of Fear / Stun in a hard fight.
All of the spells use Water / Magic as the element.
Low damage, low control, low debuffs, high healing.
Heal     Level 1 Level 2 Level 3      Heal units for 25HP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Ideas</title>
      <link>/overview/ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/ideas/</guid>
      <description>This is just a dump of ideas. Add them here for future brainstorming.
Major Game Engine Features To Be Considered Code that I haven&amp;rsquo;t added yet.
Flanking bonus Strategic positions Treasure chests Larger maps Heroes Items Difficulty Level Boss Fights Player places units Hidden units (i.e: placed behind tree)  Difficulty Level Games are annoying when you have to start them over completely &amp;ndash; especially story heavy games. One option is to offer easy mode and normal mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seige : Scene 5</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene5/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and ARCHER are atop Drysgate discussing the siege.
Stou  Report?
 Archer  They&amp;rsquo;re attacking with scout groups. Pinning us back as they continue to grow their ranks.
 Stou  Do we know why they&amp;rsquo;re attacking?
 Archer  No, sir. They&amp;rsquo;ve sent no messages. Only arrows.
 Stou  And who is that? Who leads them?
 Archer  The man in the cloak?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showdown : Scene 12</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene12/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and CASSANDRA preparing for the final battle.
Cassandra  Oh, Stou. I&amp;rsquo;m surprised you made it this far. For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, I respected your brother. Despite the fact he took everything from me. My father. My kingdom. My heritage. Was he so foolish as to think that a discarded mountain city would be suitable for one such as myself? For royalty? My birthright is to rule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soundtrack</title>
      <link>/soundtrack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/soundtrack/</guid>
      <description>Tony Manfredonia reached out to me in January 2015, and we did a brief trial. It went so smoothly that I gladly had him work on the entire soundtrack. In the end, he crafted over 30 minutes of unique content tailored to very specific aspects of the game. Below is a sample of the types of music he made along with the in game considerations.
 Main Menu I have listened to this piece thousands of times because it always loads when I&amp;rsquo;m testing, and it still hasn&amp;rsquo;t gotten old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical Notes</title>
      <link>/overview/tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/tech/</guid>
      <description>A place to store random tech notes for reference when designing things.
Modifiers There are a few types of modifiers in the game, and they are all applied in different ways. Here&amp;rsquo;s the breakdown of how a unit might get a modifier applied to it.
 Spell Modifiers: Each spell applies a modifier to the target squad / units and this can be overridden on the spell level. Spells are abilities, and they should process ability modifiers the same way combat modifiers do, but they currently don&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Victory : Scene 13</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene13/</guid>
      <description> Current cutscene implementation
No dialogue. Celebration and BARRIC&amp;rsquo;s burial.
Role credits.
TODO / DISCUSS Clean boat edge  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warning : Scene 6</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene6/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU has snuck through enemy lines while CASSANDRA catches him on his way to Wellspring.
Cassandra  Stou! I&amp;rsquo;ve ridden all night to catch you!
 Stou  Cassandra? What are you doing here? You were to notify the council.
 Cassandra  I &amp;hellip; your brother. I had to come immediately. Barric. He left South Keep shortly after you we did &amp;hellip; with those who stand against us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watchful Spells</title>
      <link>/overview/watchful/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/watchful/</guid>
      <description>Watchful spells are well balanced. They should be able to heal units, buff units, resist damage, do damage, and offer crowd control.
All of the spells use Nature as the element.
Moderate damage, moderate control, moderate debuffs, moderate healing.
Regen     Level 1 Level 2 Level 3      Heal a unit for 25 HP every tick. Purify negative effects on unit when cast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Map</title>
      <link>/overview/map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/map/</guid>
      <description>Names &amp;amp; Locations  Barric: One of the council lords, and Stou&amp;rsquo;s older brother. Stou: Stou&amp;rsquo;s younger brother who the player is controlling. Alfric: The knight Stou is talking to at the beginning. One of the council members, Barric&amp;rsquo;s equal. South Keep: Barric&amp;rsquo;s city Cassandra: Princess to king Barric overthrew. Barric still helps her. Stou has a crush. Wintry Manor: Cassandra&amp;rsquo;s ice city Mountains of Arrington: Mountain range that Wintry Manor lies in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>