<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Index on A Verse For Barric</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Index on A Verse For Barric</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Action Bar</title>
      <link>/overview/interface/actionbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/interface/actionbar/</guid>
      <description>Notes to consider:
 As Stou and units level up, make their icon housing slightly cooler based on their level. Make Stou&amp;rsquo;s / units card more elaborate also as it levels up. When Stou is casting, animate his card in some way. Make the card the thing you tap to change casting stance, and get rid of strategy button. Focus on gate opening UI and effects &amp;ndash; if that indicates the start of a wave, the player needs to know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggressive Spells</title>
      <link>/overview/abilities/aggressive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/abilities/aggressive/</guid>
      <description>Aggressive spells are meant to kill the enemy before they can kill you. This is done by direct damage, or by increasing the damage your units can do. The spells also compliment one another, so that when stacked can do massive damage.
All of the spells use Fire as the element.
High damage, low control, low debuffs, low healing.
Phoenix     Level 1 Level 2 Level 3      Dead units damage engaged target.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animations</title>
      <link>/animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/animations/</guid>
      <description>I began working with Liron Peer in late 2014 on character animations. Of all the specialties, finding an animator who could work on isometric material was the biggest challenge. I spent over $1,000 on trial runs through various animators with no luck. Once I found Liron and she nailed her first attempt, we jumped straight in to the entire contract. In total, she produced over 1,000 hand drawn frames. Here are a few of them:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Betrayal : Scene 7</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene7/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and CASSANDRA interrogating ISS&amp;rsquo;DAR after the battle.
Stou  Why do you attack us? Who leads this assault? Tell me, now.
 Iss&amp;rsquo;dar  You fool. The answer is in front of you.
 Stou  You dare give me riddles?
 Iss&amp;rsquo;dar  Are you so blind? You&amp;rsquo;ve been betrayed.
 Enemy army appears on the horizon.
Stou  We were followed &amp;hellip; how? They didn&amp;rsquo;t know we were here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boss Progression</title>
      <link>/overview/progression/boss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/progression/boss/</guid>
      <description>Sand Shaman The shaman appears in Level 3 : City and is our first encounter with a boss. This boss isn&amp;rsquo;t a boss like the others &amp;ndash; it becomes a normal champion later in the game. Other bosses are one time encounters, but this just introduces the player to dealing with enemy spell casters. So, the goal is to treat the unit like a boss during the first 2 sequences, and then make it a traditional squad based unit that can be killed for the final sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BroDown : Scene 10</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene10/</guid>
      <description> Current cutscene implementation
No dialogue. STOU kills BARRIC, and flashbacks explain how he was set up.
TODO / DISCUSS Decide if we want snow or not. Fix flashbacks based off of updated visuals. 09:19 - Glint chains to highlight he was captive NOTES: Travel dialogue to hammer home that she orchestrated all of this.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camp : Scene 11</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene11/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and ALFRIC resume there conversation from the beginning of the game, explaining why they&amp;rsquo;re gathered for war.
Stou  That&amp;rsquo;s why we&amp;rsquo;re gathered here to fight.
 Alfric  So, Barric is truly gone then. It hurts to say that out loud. That traitorous b&amp;hellip; clearly her father&amp;rsquo;s blood runs deep.
 Stou  What news of her army?
 Alfric  She marches for the castle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camp Scene</title>
      <link>/overview/interface/camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/interface/camp/</guid>
      <description>This screen will allow you to manage your army, and watch it grow.
As more units are added, more buildings start appearing in the camp. The big unknown here is if the world map should just link to the Camp, and then the Camp link to Stou, Unit and Hero Upgrades OR if the World Map should link to everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra Diversion</title>
      <link>/overview/decisions/diversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/decisions/diversion/</guid>
      <description>After Cassandra tells Stou he needs to head to the border, she offers a parting gift.
 Stou, you&amp;rsquo;ll need backup if you&amp;rsquo;re going to survive. Please take some of my soldiers, or at least allow me to teach you [Randomize a Spell she can teach him]
 Player picks, and either gets units, or a new spell for Stou.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra Leaves</title>
      <link>/overview/decisions/cassandra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/decisions/cassandra/</guid>
      <description>Melee2 leaves the party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code</title>
      <link>/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/code/</guid>
      <description>To date, this game has 38,378 lines of Swift code. There have been countless hours invested in art, story, design, animation and brainstorming, but code makes all of this tick. Behind the scenes, SpriteKit and GameplayKit power a vast majority of the engine. This section provides a look at some of the custom frameworks that had to be developed along with tricky problems that had to be solved.
The Frameworks CutsceneKit Helps develop chat overlays with custom timing and movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Spells</title>
      <link>/overview/abilities/controlling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/abilities/controlling/</guid>
      <description>Controlling spells will probably be the most difficult to play. They will requires more switching between spell categories. For example, mesmerize a unit, then switch to Protective and play for awhile, then switch back to Controlling. They also have wave based triggers (wave starts, heal units), so the player will have to switch at the correct timing.
All of the spells use Wind / Mind as the element.
Moderate damage, high control, moderate debuffs, low healing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossroads : Scene 8</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene8/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and CASSANDRA at crossroads deciding next steps.
Stou  Still they persist.
 Cassandra  Perhaps, we should split up.
 Stou  I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy the idea of dividing our forces. Or, of leaving you.
 Cassandra  Nor do I, but hear me. Lure them into the mountains, distract them, I will alert the council.
 Stou  I don&amp;rsquo;t like this, Cassandra. But, you&amp;rsquo;re right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision : Scene 4</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene4/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and CASSANDRA consult with BARRIC after the battle at SOUTH KEEP
Cassandra  Our ambush was avoided.
 Barric  I know, and had we pressed the attack, our city would have been left defenseless. We must not overreact.
 Stou  Overreact? They attacked our city, Barric. Our home!
 Barric  And who exactly are &amp;ldquo;they&amp;rdquo;?
 Stou  This matters when they bring war to our very doorstep?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distraction : Scene 3</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene3/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and CASSANDRA notice the main force bypassed their ambush and is marching on South Keep.
Cassandra  The whole of their forces approaches the city!
 Stou  How did they get past us?
 Cassandra  It seems the attack was but a small diversion all the while the real threat marched from the south.
 Stou  They knew we were waiting. But &amp;hellip; how?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enemy Progression</title>
      <link>/overview/progression/enemy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/progression/enemy/</guid>
      <description>These are the units that the player will fight against. The goal is for each one to present a specific challenege so that the player will learn how to counter them.
Bad Melee 1 : Border Squires This is the first and most common enemy unit, and it counters Melee 1. Also allows for the largest enemy squads. Only has a base attack. Gradually levels up and sticks around throughout the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fjord : Scene 9</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene9/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and TOWNSMEN discussing why the Manor has been abandoned.
Stou  Townsmen, where is everyone?
 Townsmen  They left, sir. About 2 3 weeks past. Marching towards the war.
 Stou  2 3 weeks ago? The war hadn&amp;rsquo;t begun yet. Who ordered this?
 Townsmen  Orders came down from &amp;hellip; Sir! We&amp;rsquo;re under attack!
 TODO / DISCUSS 08:41 - Revisit snow effect 08:45 - Blinking Stou 08:52 - Something like pan to incoming army, change in dialogue, or somehting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friendly Support</title>
      <link>/overview/decisions/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/decisions/support/</guid>
      <description>Figure out a way to introduce Flail1 or Melee3. Maybe a decision from earlier in the game, and then that unit that you supported is waiting for you at border to help you? Need to add a melee unit here because Melee2 leave shortly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friendly Units</title>
      <link>/overview/progression/friendly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/progression/friendly/</guid>
      <description>These are the units that the player will be able to recruit throughout the game. One playthrough will not guarantee all units are collected. Some are either-or type decisions. Also, once a unit has been obtained, there is still a chance they will leave. The goal is for the army size to be consistent, which will keep the game balanced.
Melee 1 : Lemon Knights This unit begins the game with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gameplay Progression</title>
      <link>/overview/progression/gameplay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/progression/gameplay/</guid>
      <description>:question: Decision : Select your base magic type.
Before the player begins, they can choose their preferred magic type. This selection will allow Level 1 to be played without interruption.
:movie_camera: Movie : Intro : Scene 1
Explains Barric&amp;rsquo;s backstory, and establishes where the player is now. Scene is actually the same scene as level 12, since the first 11 levels are played in the past and the player is brought up to real time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giant</title>
      <link>/overview/decisions/giant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/decisions/giant/</guid>
      <description>Some sort of decision that would allow the giant to join your party. Ideas:
 In combat, hint that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t kill the giant. If you do, you get cool loot. If you leave him along, he&amp;rsquo;ll attack the enemy, and join you after the battle.
 Same concept, but just in the decision screen. After battle, notice giant is wounded. Heal him and leave, or finish him off. Rewards are the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping Hand</title>
      <link>/overview/decisions/hand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/decisions/hand/</guid>
      <description>Decide between helping Melee3 or Flail1, and that unit will join your army just before Level 7.
 As you prepare to leave the town, you notice wounded soldiers regrouping. Do you want to help a nearby shield bearer carry his friend to the medic, or help calm a crazed flail-man over his presumed losses?
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illustrations</title>
      <link>/illustrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/illustrations/</guid>
      <description>Scott Pellico was a godsend for this project. After a few trial runs with other artists, I was having trouble establishing an art direction. My brother, Chris, found Scott for his project. Since Chris didn&amp;rsquo;t need Scott full time, Scott agreed to split his work between the two of us. He worked on the project part time for nearly a year starting in 2014. Before getting into specific contributions, here is a gallery of some of my favorite Scott creations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro : Scene 1</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene1/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and ALFRIC gathered amongst soldiers setting up camp.
Stou  You&amp;rsquo;ve met my brother, Barric?
 Alfric  Met him? I&amp;rsquo;ve fought with him, and would again. Fine warrior, and a better man.
 Stou  I never knew that side of him. I&amp;rsquo;ve only heard stories.
 Alfric  Story like his &amp;hellip; words only carry so much. Don&amp;rsquo;t do it justice. Barric saved this kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intruder : Scene 2</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene2/</guid>
      <description>STOU and ALFRIC and CASSANDRA examining an invaders corpse.
Cassandra  These markings, this soldier is from the Drylands. This makes no sense. What would prompt such an attack?
 Stou  We need to find out. We&amp;rsquo;ll track those who escaped.
 Barric  No. We must return to South Keep and warn our people.
 Stou  Turn back? And what then, Barric? Wait to be attacked again?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 1 : Forest</title>
      <link>/overview/levels/level1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/levels/level1/</guid>
      <description>21 days ago &amp;hellip;
As they do each year, Stou, Barric and Cassandra&amp;rsquo;s were hauling supplies to prepare Wintry Manor for the coming winter. Shortly into the trip, their camp was ambushed by unknown assailants.
 Wooden Falls Summary This level introduces the player to movement, melee combat/charging, ranged combat, unit resistances and casting spells. It also teaches the player about the threat of enemy archers, and the concept of incoming waves of enemies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 1 to Level 2</title>
      <link>/overview/travel/1to2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/travel/1to2/</guid>
      <description> The border clans haven’t attacked us like this in years. Who&amp;rsquo;s organizing this? And why? No matter &amp;hellip; if it&amp;rsquo;s a fight they want, it&amp;rsquo;s a fight they&amp;rsquo;ll get.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 10 : Farm</title>
      <link>/overview/levels/level10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/levels/level10/</guid>
      <description>  Earlier today
As Stou left the mountains, he could not accept that he killed Barric, nor could he accept his inability to see betrayal that was right in front of him. His lust for battle lost him a brother. So, he wandered on. Perhaps the burning farm in the distance would provide him with a purpose.
 Wheatsbury </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 10 to Level 11</title>
      <link>/overview/travel/10to11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/travel/10to11/</guid>
      <description> A friendly force gathers nearby. There is still a chance to preserve what Barric sacrificed so much for. I owe it to my brother to try and help.
 OR
 My brothers spirit lives on. I will join the rally to support all that he sacrificed for. Barric &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m so sorry.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 11 : Camp</title>
      <link>/overview/levels/level11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/levels/level11/</guid>
      <description>  Present day
In agreement that Cassandra must be stopped, Stou and Alfric began preparing the camp to march first thing in the morning. Stou urged his men to [Fill with prior decision: enjoy one last night of drinking OR get some rest].
 Booming Hills </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 11 to Level 12</title>
      <link>/overview/travel/11to12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/travel/11to12/</guid>
      <description> I stoked the flames of war and they engulfed everything I touched. Barric died because of me. Because I wouldn’t listen, and now everything he fought to protect, could be destroyed. Cassandra must be stopped.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 12 : Castle (Boss)</title>
      <link>/overview/levels/level12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/levels/level12/</guid>
      <description>  Negotiation will no longer work as Cassandra, the ice princess, is determined to become Queen and rule once again. Stou can only hope to defend the castle and preserve the fair and free lands that his brother sacrificed so much for to create.
 Castle Endridge </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 2 : Hills</title>
      <link>/overview/levels/level2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/levels/level2/</guid>
      <description>19 days ago &amp;hellip;
Barric refused to make a rash judgement regarding the intruders. Set in his resolve, he returned to South Keep to gather more information. Meanwhile, anxious to punish their attackers, Stou and Cassandra set up an ambush should the enemy pursue.
 Highlands Summary This level teaches the player how to switch spell categories, control war machines, friendly fire and strategic positions, and enemy champions. A unit is also guaranteed to level up here, which will teach the player how to pick skills in the Camp scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 2 to Level 3</title>
      <link>/overview/travel/2to3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/travel/2to3/</guid>
      <description> They&amp;rsquo;re well trained. And well armed. This must be an organized invasion. Good, I&amp;rsquo;m ready to prove myself.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 3 : City (Boss)</title>
      <link>/overview/levels/level3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/levels/level3/</guid>
      <description>16 days ago &amp;hellip;
Stou and Cassandra suspect an insider may have alerted the enemy to their trap since the bulk of the invading forces are now unscathed, marching on South Keep. With little time to ponder, they rush to Barric&amp;rsquo;s aid.
 South Keep Summary Intro to the first enemy boss, treasure chests, a defensive objective (if enemy destroys the gate, they win), and the first true gameplay choice with strategic positions (over extend and risk getting flanked).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 3 to Level 3a</title>
      <link>/overview/travel/3to3a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/travel/3to3a/</guid>
      <description> My brother is as stubborn as an ox. While he wastes time with words our enemy gathers. Eventually, I will greet those who threaten us.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 3a : Change of Plans</title>
      <link>/overview/levels/level3a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/levels/level3a/</guid>
      <description>Table Lakes This level has no combat, so it should be a cool experience for the player. Army is marching through terrain, and Cassandra approaches surround by her person guard and 2 squads of Melee2 knights. She explains the situation to Stou, and he changes paths to go to the border while she moves towards council.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 3a to Level 4</title>
      <link>/overview/travel/3ato4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/travel/3ato4/</guid>
      <description> Good, the princess will spread the word while I head to the front lines to see first hand what&amp;rsquo;s really happening.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 4 : Border</title>
      <link>/overview/levels/level4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/levels/level4/</guid>
      <description>11 days ago &amp;hellip;
While Barric ordered Stou to notify the council of the invasion, Cassandra alerted him to more pressing matters in the Drylands. Stou arrives at Drysgate to offer reinforcements for the siege while Cassandra, in his stead, agrees to notify the council lords.
 Drysgate Summary    Friendly Squads Enemy Squads     Melee1 BadMelee1   Melee2 BadArcher1   Archer1 Champion   Trebuchet / Catapult Shaman   Crossbowmen / Longbowmen BadMelee2    Spearmen    Ykesha    First Cutscene Scouting party is returning with the enemy on their heels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 4 to Level 5</title>
      <link>/overview/travel/4to5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/travel/4to5/</guid>
      <description> Even as they press further into our lands, we still know nothing of our enemy, their leader, or their motivations. I must find answers.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 5 : Desert</title>
      <link>/overview/levels/level5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/levels/level5/</guid>
      <description>9 days ago
During a pause in the border assault, a clearing allowed Stou to venture further into the Drylands so that he could learn more about the invaders. While traveling to Wellspring, Cassandra caught up in a panic and notified him that Barric was seen with the enemy, and may be organizing the attacks.
 Red Canyon Summary Introduce the user to the concept of invisible units. Also, an interesting side mission to the standard plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 5 to Level 6</title>
      <link>/overview/travel/5to6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/travel/5to6/</guid>
      <description> Something’s not right. Barric would never destroy what he fought so hard to preserve. Would he? What am I missing?
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 6 : Oasis (Boss)</title>
      <link>/overview/levels/level6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/levels/level6/</guid>
      <description>  8 days ago &amp;hellip;
Refusing to believe that Barric could be a traitor, Stou and Cassandra continued upland towards Wellspring. Hoping to find answers, they instead arrived to an uncooperative host.
 Wellspring </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 6 to Level 7</title>
      <link>/overview/travel/6to7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/travel/6to7/</guid>
      <description> Even in death these cowards believe that their cause is just. Why are they so relentless? I fear we may never discover the truth.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 7 : Foothills</title>
      <link>/overview/levels/level7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/levels/level7/</guid>
      <description>7 days ago &amp;hellip;
With such a large army in pursuit, Stou and Cassandra were left with no choice but to flee back towards Endria&amp;rsquo;s mainland. Annoyed that he was left with riddles instead of answers, Stou opened his mind to the possibility that his brother would betray him.
 Border Steppes Phase 1, rescue guys near house:
&amp;ldquo;Stou!, Sorry, er&amp;hellip;sir. You helped us back in Barric&amp;rsquo;s City. We figured we&amp;rsquo;d return the favor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 7 to Level 8</title>
      <link>/overview/travel/7to8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/travel/7to8/</guid>
      <description> Our enemies’ numbers continue to grow like a weed. Cassandra must reach the council and secure their aid. I only hope it’s not too late.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 7a : Crossroads</title>
      <link>/overview/levels/level7a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/levels/level7a/</guid>
      <description> Another exclamation icon on the world map instead of a sword. Just a trigger for the crossroads video.
Crossroads </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 8 : Mountain</title>
      <link>/overview/levels/level8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/levels/level8/</guid>
      <description>  5 days ago
Cassandra and Stou split forces. Cassandra quickly went east to notify the council of the coming invasion. Meanwhile, Stou began the trek up Giant&amp;rsquo;s Pass to lure the enemy through the treacherous mountains of Arrington. Before Stou&amp;rsquo;s slow moving forces can reach reinforcements at Wintry Manor, an enemy advance party catches up.
 Giant&amp;rsquo;s Pass </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 8 to Level 9</title>
      <link>/overview/travel/8to9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/travel/8to9/</guid>
      <description> Their main forces aren&amp;rsquo;t far behind. We must hurry to Wintry Manor for reinforcements, and to make a stand.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 9 : Fjord (Boss)</title>
      <link>/overview/levels/level9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/levels/level9/</guid>
      <description>  3 days ago
Stou arrives at Wintry Manor to find it cold and deserted. Where has everyone gone? Stou begins his search for answers knowing that time is not on his side, and that the enemy is nearly at their doorstep.
 Wintry Manor </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level 9 to Level 10</title>
      <link>/overview/travel/9to10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/travel/9to10/</guid>
      <description>Silence, to try to create a dramatic effect indicating Stou is sorry for Barric&amp;rsquo;s death. World map music may be toned down / altered during this sequence too.
OR
Use dialogue to explain to players who didn&amp;rsquo;t follow that she did this.
 Cassandra &amp;hellip; power isn&amp;rsquo;t enough for you? You had to manipulate me &amp;hellip; to use me against my own family?
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loot City</title>
      <link>/overview/decisions/loot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/decisions/loot/</guid>
      <description>After combat, Stou has the option to loot the city.
 As you retreat from the city, you notice valuable artifacts in storefronts. Do you want to order your men to grab what they can, or leave the city folk and their belongings untouched?
 Two potential outcomes to brainstorm here.
 Spearmen stay/go depending on decision.  a. If you loot, you get an item, a spell, food and gold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motion Graphics</title>
      <link>/motion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/motion/</guid>
      <description>The term motion graphics doesn&amp;rsquo;t justify the help that Brian Campbell provided on this project. He began contributing in March 2015 as a video editor for cutscenes. That alone was huge. At the time, I had the story written and art for the scenes designed. I quickly stitched them together in iMovie to get a sense for pacing. Fortunately, Brian does this stuff for a living so he knew exactly what needed to happen to move things forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Game : Magic</title>
      <link>/overview/decisions/newgame/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/decisions/newgame/</guid>
      <description>Black screen, Stou&amp;rsquo;s image in bottom left.
 Stou, you&amp;rsquo;ve been learning magic for some time now. Has any specialization resonated with you?
 Explain the 4 specializations.
Player picks one, fade to black, start cutscene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protective Spells</title>
      <link>/overview/abilities/protective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/abilities/protective/</guid>
      <description>Protective spells are meant to keep your friendlies alive. This is done by direct healing, revival, or by limiting the amount of damage an enemy can do. Crowd control is minimal, with Smite being the only hope of Fear / Stun in a hard fight.
All of the spells use Water / Magic as the element.
Low damage, low control, low debuffs, high healing.
Heal     Level 1 Level 2 Level 3      Heal units for 25HP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Ideas</title>
      <link>/overview/ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/ideas/</guid>
      <description>This is just a dump of ideas. Add them here for future brainstorming.
Major Game Engine Features To Be Considered Code that I haven&amp;rsquo;t added yet.
Flanking bonus Strategic positions Treasure chests Larger maps Heroes Items Difficulty Level Boss Fights Player places units Hidden units (i.e: placed behind tree)  Difficulty Level Games are annoying when you have to start them over completely &amp;ndash; especially story heavy games. One option is to offer easy mode and normal mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranged Help</title>
      <link>/overview/decisions/ranged/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/decisions/ranged/</guid>
      <description>Before Level 4 : Border, Stou will be given a choice between crossbowmen and longbowmen.
 You&amp;rsquo;ll need some arrows to keep the waves at bay. Have a squad of mine. Longbowmen can shoot over obstacles at great distance. Crossbowmen don&amp;rsquo;t shoot as far, but they sure do pack a punch.
 Since the crazy enemy that charges into troops and explodes is introduced, the extra archers will help kill them before they can do major damage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rest or Party</title>
      <link>/overview/decisions/rest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/decisions/rest/</guid>
      <description>While camping for the night before marching to meet Cassandra.
 Your men seem nervous. Do you want to encourage them to sleep and focus or drink, dance and celebrate their potentially limited days?
 Celebrate can give some sort of anti-fear, +strength buff during the coming ambush. Sleep can give regenerate, or some other aide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seige : Scene 5</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene5/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and ARCHER are atop Drysgate discussing the siege.
Stou  Report?
 Archer  They&amp;rsquo;re attacking with scout groups. Pinning us back as they continue to grow their ranks.
 Stou  Do we know why they&amp;rsquo;re attacking?
 Archer  No, sir. They&amp;rsquo;ve sent no messages. Only arrows.
 Stou  And who is that? Who leads them?
 Archer  The man in the cloak?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showdown : Scene 12</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene12/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU and CASSANDRA preparing for the final battle.
Cassandra  Oh, Stou. I&amp;rsquo;m surprised you made it this far. For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, I respected your brother. Despite the fact he took everything from me. My father. My kingdom. My heritage. Was he so foolish as to think that a discarded mountain city would be suitable for one such as myself? For royalty? My birthright is to rule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Siege Planning</title>
      <link>/overview/decisions/planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/decisions/planning/</guid>
      <description>It looks like enemy forces are controlling the city. We&amp;rsquo;ll have to defeat them before the locals will provide us with information. In preparation, would you like to sharpen our arrows or our blades?
 Permanent, +1 Strength to either archer class units or melee class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soundtrack</title>
      <link>/soundtrack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/soundtrack/</guid>
      <description>Tony Manfredonia reached out to me in January 2015, and we did a brief trial. It went so smoothly that I gladly had him work on the entire soundtrack. In the end, he crafted over 30 minutes of unique content tailored to very specific aspects of the game. Below is a sample of the types of music he made along with the in game considerations.
 Main Menu I have listened to this piece thousands of times because it always loads when I&amp;rsquo;m testing, and it still hasn&amp;rsquo;t gotten old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spearmen</title>
      <link>/overview/decisions/spearmen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/decisions/spearmen/</guid>
      <description>After Level 4 : Border, a decision level will appear on the world map (same as when Cassandra diverted Stou to border). Note: Have to decide if this is played out in the battle view, or just in Decision mode.
 A word, stranger? We&amp;rsquo;re not sure why our brother are invading your lands, but we do not approve. Something evil is motivating them, and we hope to stop it. May we join your ranks?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stou&#39;s Abilities</title>
      <link>/overview/abilities/stou/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/abilities/stou/</guid>
      <description>The goal with Stou is to support 4 major play styles.
 Aggressive: Damage based spells that try to kill &amp;amp; fear the enemy before they get to your army. Example: fireball Watchful: Buffs, debuffs, haste, traps and abilities that aid you army in defeating the enemy. Balanced play style. Protective: Heals, buffs to increase the survivability of the army. Controlling: Using spells to sleep, mesmerize, charm, root, and make the enemy flee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical Notes</title>
      <link>/overview/tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/tech/</guid>
      <description>A place to store random tech notes for reference when designing things.
Modifiers There are a few types of modifiers in the game, and they are all applied in different ways. Here&amp;rsquo;s the breakdown of how a unit might get a modifier applied to it.
 Spell Modifiers: Each spell applies a modifier to the target squad / units and this can be overridden on the spell level. Spells are abilities, and they should process ability modifiers the same way combat modifiers do, but they currently don&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traps</title>
      <link>/overview/decisions/traps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/decisions/traps/</guid>
      <description>The steep, snowy terrain has slowed down your march. Enemy scouting parties will catch up any day now. Should we set up traps, or fortify our defenses?
 Traps could make the enemy spawn damaged, or even have a visual like snow falling. Fortify could put barriers down that the enemy has to break, or increase defense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Units &amp; Their Progression</title>
      <link>/overview/progression/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/progression/notes/</guid>
      <description>Unit progression is a tricky topic and requires a lot of play testing to truly balance it. So, to start, I&amp;rsquo;m approaching it at a basic level that has room to be tailored. The order in which Friendly Units, Enemy Units and Boss Units appear is fairly though out, but their attributes and abilities are currently in a basic state.
The overall goal is for Stou (the player) to be the deciding factor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Victory : Scene 13</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene13/</guid>
      <description> Current cutscene implementation
No dialogue. Celebration and BARRIC&amp;rsquo;s burial.
Role credits.
TODO / DISCUSS Clean boat edge  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War Machine</title>
      <link>/overview/decisions/warmachine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/decisions/warmachine/</guid>
      <description>Before Level 2 begins, prompt the user to make a choice.
 Sir, what should we construct to aid our ambush? The trebuchet scatters rocks over a wide range while the catapult deals direct, accurate damage.
 Whichever the user selects gets added to the army.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warning : Scene 6</title>
      <link>/overview/cutscenes/scene6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/cutscenes/scene6/</guid>
      <description>Current cutscene implementation
STOU has snuck through enemy lines while CASSANDRA catches him on his way to Wellspring.
Cassandra  Stou! I&amp;rsquo;ve ridden all night to catch you!
 Stou  Cassandra? What are you doing here? You were to notify the council.
 Cassandra  I &amp;hellip; your brother. I had to come immediately. Barric. He left South Keep shortly after you we did &amp;hellip; with those who stand against us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watchful Spells</title>
      <link>/overview/abilities/watchful/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/abilities/watchful/</guid>
      <description>Watchful spells are well balanced. They should be able to heal units, buff units, resist damage, do damage, and offer crowd control.
All of the spells use Nature as the element.
Moderate damage, moderate control, moderate debuffs, moderate healing.
Regen     Level 1 Level 2 Level 3      Heal a unit for 25 HP every tick. Purify negative effects on unit when cast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Map</title>
      <link>/overview/interface/map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/interface/map/</guid>
      <description>Names &amp;amp; Locations  Barric: One of the council lords, and Stou&amp;rsquo;s older brother. Stou: Stou&amp;rsquo;s younger brother who the player is controlling. Alfric: The knight Stou is talking to at the beginning. One of the council members, Barric&amp;rsquo;s equal. South Keep: Barric&amp;rsquo;s city Cassandra: Princess to king Barric overthrew. Barric still helps her. Stou has a crush. Wintry Manor: Cassandra&amp;rsquo;s ice city Mountains of Arrington: Mountain range that Wintry Manor lies in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>